导　　演： 理查德・弗莱舍
她的名字叫桑妮亚
她生活在一个野蛮的世界
一个充满暴力的时代
一个长着红头发的勇猛战士
在希伯来王国
她为追求正义和复仇
将成为一个传奇
这便是传奇的开始
Sonja.
桑妮亚
You are suffering, Sonja...
你正饱受痛苦，桑妮亚……
but vengeance shall be yours.
但你应该复仇
Vengeance on Queen Gedren...
找戈登女王复仇
who wanted you for herself.
那个为了她自己的利益而通缉你的人
Your disgust was clear.
你非常痛恨他们
And so it was that Gedren
ordered your family murdered...
是戈登下令杀害你的家人……
your body violated by her soldiers.
你的肉体被她的士兵侵犯
But in your quest
for justice and vengeance...
但你在寻求正义和复仇时
you will need great strength...
你将需要强大的力量……
for your sword arm must have no equal.
没有东西能比你手上的剑厉害
I give you that strength.
我来给你这样的力量
神剑女王
主演：阿诺德・施瓦辛格
主演：布里吉特・尼尔森
饰 桑妮亚
主演：桑多尔・伯格曼
主演：保罗・史密夫
主演：厄尼・雷斯
主演：约翰・拉里斯
服装设计：达尼路・多内蒂
音乐制作：埃尼奥・莫里康
制片主任：A.迈克・力伯曼
编剧：Frank J. Urioste, A.C.E
摄影指导：GIUSEPPE ROTUNND, A.I.C.A.S.C
造型设计：罗伯特・E・霍华德
编剧：Clive Exton
乔治・麦克唐纳・弗雷泽
制片：CHRISTIAN FERRY
导演：理查德・弗莱舍
Varna, where is the Lord of Hyrkania?
瓦尔纳，赫卡尼亚君主在哪里？
He has not come, Highness.
他没有来，汉斯。
He should be here
for the destruction of the talisman.
他应该在这儿
为了这毁灭性的神器
But we cannot delay.
We will proceed without him.
但是我们不能拖延
即使没有他也要继续进行
O God of the high Gods...
上帝啊!崇高的上帝啊……
behold the talisman with which
you created the world and all things.
看你创造世界和所有事物的神器
O God of Gods...
上帝啊上帝……
it has become too powerful for us...
它将变得过于强大而使我们无法控制……
and we must destroy it
before it destroys the world.
在它毁灭世界之前我们必须摧毁它
Forgive us now
as we send it out of the light...
原谅我们
我们将让它离开光芒……
from which it draws its power...
因为光芒能使它获得力量……
into eternal darkness.
我们要使它进入永恒的黑暗之中。
Forgive us.
原谅我们
Come on.
来吧
So this can make worlds...
它可以创造世界……
or shatter them by storm and earthquake.
但也可以制造风暴和地震毁灭世界
Have it lifted out.
把它抬出来
Lift it out!
抬出来!
Touch it.
触摸它一下
So it is true. Only women may touch it.
证明这是正确的，只有女人可以碰它。
The cover.
盖起来
Take it out.
抬出去
Great queen,
what shall we do with the prisoners?
伟大的女王
我们应该怎么处置囚犯?
- No!
不!
Come.
跟我来
Horses.
备马
The talisman's stolen.
神器被偷人走了
Must destroy the talisman.
必须毁坏这个神器
We must find my sister. Take me.
我们必须找到我的妹妹，请带我走
I know where she is. Please.
我知道她在哪儿，拜托了
Magnificent.
很好
You have nothing more to learn, Sonja.
这里没有东西可以供你学习了，桑妮亚
You are the master of the master.
你非常优秀
Never have I seen your equal.
你是无可匹敌的
You must learn to like men a little better.
你必须学会对男人好一点
They are not all evil.
他们并不是所有都是邪恶的
We must judge by our own experience,
Grand Master.
我们必须根据我们的经验判断
长老
I know.
我知道
But in life, all is not swordplay.
但人并不是为了剑术而活着
Hatred of men in a lovely young woman...
在一个美丽的年轻女子憎恨男人时……
it could be your downfall.
它会令你垮台
I don't hate all men, Grand Master.
我并不恨所有的男人，长老
That would have been music to my ears
30 years ago.
那是30年前我听到的声音
Come.
来吧
A great swordsman
must have a great sword.
一个杰出的剑客必须有一把好剑
Choose.
挑选吧
A gift from the Grand Master.
作为长老给你的礼物
Sonja.
桑妮亚
What is it, Red Sonja?
怎么了？桑妮亚
I'm looking for Red Sonja.
我在寻找桑妮亚
- I am Sonja.
- Your sister's dying.
我是桑妮亚
你姐姐快要死了
I'll take you to her.
我带你去见她
Varna.
瓦尔纳
Thank God.
谢天谢地
I've lived long enough.
我终于坚持活到现在了
The talisman's stolen.
神器被偷了
All the priests massacred.
所有的神父被屠杀
- We fought...
- Rest, Varna. Later we can talk.
我们要战斗
休息一下，瓦尔纳，我们可以晚点再说
There's no time. Listen.
没有时间了，听着
The talisman has terrible power...
这个神器有着恐怖的力量……
which grows in the light.
它随着光照而成长
In 13 days it could destroy the world...
它会在13天内毁灭世界……
by storm and earthquake.
利用风暴和地震
You must destroy the talisman, Sonja.
你必须毁坏这神器，桑妮亚
Send it into darkness. Swear that you will.
你要对此发誓，使它进入永恒的黑暗之中
I swear.
我发誓
Who took it?
谁抢走了它?
I don't know.
我不知道
There was a woman with a gold mask.
是一个带金面具的女人
Soldiers.
和她的士兵们
Where did they take it? North? South?
他们带到哪儿去了?北方?南方?
She's dead.
And the living have work to do.
她死了
我们活着的人做事去吧
Her work, my work, is no concern of yours.
她的事，我的事，这与你没有关系
- Who are you, anyway?
- My name is Kalidor.
告诉我你是谁?
我叫凯利多
I befriended your sister, remember?
我照顾过你姐姐，记得么?
I'm a friend of yours, too.
我也是你的朋友
I thank you for what you did for my sister.
You will be rewarded.
谢谢你为我姐姐做的这些
我会给你赏金
I'm no mercenary. Nobody pays me.
我不是为了钱，不需要付给我钱
If I think somebody owes me something,
I take it.
如果我认为有人亏欠我什么
我会自己带走
Someone is using the talisman.
有人在使用神器
- What place is that?
- Hablok. It's a great city.
那是什么地方?
哈勃洛克，一个大城市
Where are you going?
你要去哪里?
Hablok.
哈勃洛克
Wait. I'll come with you.
等一下，我和你一起去
Why should you? It's no business of yours.
你为什么要去?这与你无关
And neither am I.
你与我也没有关系
You may be wrong on both counts.
你可能两个都弄错了
I know you're a brave girl,
but danger is my trade.
我知道你是勇敢的女孩
但冒险是我的职业
Then I'll learn it by myself.
我会自己学会这些
Don't make me angry, Kalidor.
不要令我发怒，凯利多
I don't need any man's help.
我不需要任何男人帮助
Don't shake it, fool. Hold it steady!
Can you do nothing right?
不要晃动它，笨蛋，稳住它!
你能不能做点像样的?
Still, you great idiot.
稳住，你个大笨蛋
I'm trying, Your Highness.
我在努力，殿下
Clumsy oaf. Stupid, dumb,
useless, selfish beast!
笨蛋，傻瓜，蠢货
没用的东西，讨厌的家伙!
Quickly, come. Come to me.
快点，过来，到我这边来
Don't give me orders, slave.
I'll have you hung by the heels.
不要对我发号施令，奴隶
我要给你戴上脚镣
Anyway, it's too slippery.
不管它有多滑
Do you want me to fall
in that boiling mud? You numskull.
你想让我掉入这些沸腾的泥浆中吗?
你这个笨蛋
I'll try to swing it around. Now.
现在我要转动了
- Hold still, boy.
- Boy?
站着不要动，小孩
小孩?
Steady, Your Majesty. Steady.
稳住，陛下，稳住
Jump off. Jump.
跳下来，跳
What about me?
我怎么办?
Get back here and stop playing the fool.
回到这儿，不要再做蠢事
I hear and obey, master of the world.
I'm coming.
我听你的，世界的主
我来了
Lucky for you that this person came along.
向前来的这个人，你真幸运
Reward her, and tell her who I am.
奖赏给她，告诉她我是谁
His Royal Highness, the Prince Tarn,
Great Lord of Hablok...
他是塔纳王子
伟大的哈勃洛克君主
keeper of the spotless throne...
保持纯洁的王位
great elephant who fertilizes the world
with his...
像大象一样高大，他肥沃大地用他的……
I've told you not to say that.
我告诉过你不要说那些
Do it again, and I'll have you impaled.
下次再这样我会把你钉在桩上
Well, reward her, fool.
很好，奖赏给她，笨蛋
From the look of your kingdom, Prince,
you need this more than I do.
从你的王国看，王子
你比我更需要这个
Did she address me?
她在跟我说话么?
What happened?
发生了什么事?
Queen Gedren attacked us
is what happened.
就是戈登女王在攻击我们
Gedren? Queen Gedren?
戈登?戈登女王?
That's right.
对
She knocked down half the city with her
new weapon and demanded our surrender.
她用她的新武器攻下了我们半座城池
并且要求我们投降
My army ran away.
我的军队跑了
Do they want to live forever?
难道他们以为那样会活长一点?
I refused to surrender.
我绝不投降
So she knocked down the other half.
她又攻下了另一半
Falkon, since everyone is dead
or run away...
法拉肯，自从所有人死了或跑了……
you shall escort me
to the mountains tomorrow.
你明天必须护送我到山上去
I shall raise a new army...
我要建立一支新的军队
and crush this upstart Gedren underfoot.
并且击败戈登，将她踩在脚下
Where can I find her, this Queen Gedren?
在哪儿我能找到她，这个戈登女王?
In Burkubane, the land of eternal night.
在布拉库班，一块黑暗之地
How do I get there?
我可以如何去哪里?
There's a long scenic way, and there's
the short way through Brytag's toll road.
远路是穿过景色优美的地带过去，
近路是穿过布拉塔格大门过去
I'll take Brytag's toll road.
Which way is that?
我想穿过布拉塔格大门去
怎么走?
Straight north from here.
You can't miss it.
一直向北走
你不会迷路的
But it's worth a try.
但这值得一试
Ask the woman
if she wishes to join my army.
告诉这个女人
如果她愿意加入我的军队
We'll probably need a cook.
我们可能会需要厨师
Your Highness is too kind,
but I travel alone.
殿下你太友善了
但是我喜欢独行
Dismiss the woman, Falkon.
I shall dine in an hour.
叫这个女人退下，法拉肯
我一个小时后将要吃饭
May I give you a word of advice?
我可以给你一字忠告么?
Put him over your knee
and beat some manners into him.
把他放到你膝盖上
礼貌的敲他几下
You wouldn't happen to have a tablecloth,
would you?
你没有马鞍
需要么?
Brytag, come down and open the gate.
布拉塔格，把门放下并打开
Not so fast, redhead.
没这么快，红发人
I'm up here
where I can get a better look at you.
抬起头来
那样能看你清楚一点
I have no time to waste, Brytag.
我没有时间了，布拉塔格
I have plenty. Come up, I say.
我有的是时间，头起头来
- Come here, wench.
- Why should I?
过来吧，姑娘
我为什么要过来?
Because I am Brytag. This is my land.
因为我是布拉塔格，这是我的地盘
All that pass through pay me tribute.
所有要通过的人须给我贡物
- How much, Brytag?
- Who mentioned money?
要多少?布拉塔格
谁说要钱的?
Tribute, I said.
我说了，贡物
The tender kind all women pay to Brytag.
把女人温柔的东西给布拉塔格
Suppose I don't.
我想我不会
Suppose, instead, I open up
that great fat belly of yours.
相反的，我想将你开膛破肚
You hear that?
你听到她说什么了么?
She's going to open up my great...
她要切开我的……
Woman, I have fought 177 men.
女人，我过去和177个男子战斗过
Only one survives, and he has got no legs.
只有一个生还，但他失去了胳膊
You dare to mock at Brytag?
你胆敢取笑我布拉塔格?
That takes no daring.
有什么不敢的
But when I've killed you,
will your warriors let me go unharmed?
但当我杀了你
你的武士能不能让我平安过去?
When you've killed me?
当你杀了我?
When this wench has killed me,
you will let her go unharmed, won't you?
当这个女人杀了我
你可以让她平安过去，明白么?
Aye.
好
See?
看?
So, wench.
就这样，女人
I'm gonna feed your eyes
to the birds, red hair.
我要把你的眼睛喂鸟，红发女人
I don't need eyes to find you.
我不需要眼睛找你
I can smell you at a hundred paces.
一百步内我能闻到你
I will tell the future in your entrails,
red woman.
我会在你内脏告诉你将来的事，
红发女人
I know my future. You have none.
我知道我的将来，而你没有
Hold on, Sonja.
坚持住，桑妮亚
Sonja, come on.
桑妮亚，来吧
Look out!
看外面
This way. Follow me!
这边，跟着我!
- Get away. Go!
- What about you?
离开，走!
你怎么办?
I can hold them. Go!
我可以坚持住，走!
Hurry! Stop them!
快!拦住他们!
Release me, ruffian!
放开我，恶棍
Release me, I say!
我说了，放开我!
- Tell us where it is.
- I'll have your head for this!
告诉我这是哪儿
我带你们到这儿!
Don't be shy.
不要害怕
The gold, boy. Where's the gold?
黄金，小孩，黄金在哪儿?
There is no gold, ruffian.
这儿没有黄金，恶棍
I tell you, I have no gold!
我告诉你，我没有黄金!
You have fine raiment, boy,
almost as resplendent as mine.
你有华丽的服饰，小孩
几乎和我们差不多华丽
And you expect me to believe
you're penniless?
我们会相信你身无分文么?
I'll have you know, villain,
I am Prince Tarn of Hablok.
我要你们知道，恶棍
我是哈勃洛克王子
My subjects will see
to your punishment for this.
我会使你们为此受到惩罚
And a grievous punishment it will be,
impertinent oaf!
会有严重的惩罚
无理的呆子!
Your subjects?
你的麻烦?
My kingdom is greater than yours.
我的王国比你们的大
And I have but four.
虽然我只排行第四
Pull him!
拉他过来!
- Are you all right, your sovereign Majesty?
- Yes, clumsy oaf.
你没事吧，王子殿下
是的，笨蛋
Why did you leave him?
你为什么不在他身边?
We needed food. I went hunting.
我们需要食物，我打猎去了
You could have taken him with you.
你可以让他跟你一起去
Tell her, Falkon,
that I don't care for hunting.
告诉她，法拉肯
我不喜欢打猎
He doesn't care for hunting.
他不喜欢打猎
Treasure to the vaults,
prisoners to the dungeons.
珠宝放到金库里
囚犯押到地牢处
Take the talisman back
to the Chamber of Lights.
把神器抬到有光的地方去
Very well, my queen.
好的，我的女王
Perhaps fewer candles...
或许一些蜡烛……
would be advisable, Your Majesty.
是可取的，陛下
Why?
为什么?
The stronger the light, the greater
the power of the talisman grows.
光越强，神器的能量也会越强
I want more light here, not less.
我要这儿更多的光，不是一点点
But it is dangerously powerful already,
great queen.
但它已经有毁灭性的力量了
伟大的女王
- Look what it did to Hablok.
- Yes. Very satisfying.
看它击败哈勃洛克
是的，非常满意
But I want its full power
when we march against Toktyl, Ikol.
但我想要它全部的力量
当我们攻打塔克特，阿克罗时
Its full power.
需要全部力量
- It will be beyond our control, Majesty.
- Majesty!
那样它将使我们无法控制的，陛下
陛下!
Enemies are approaching
the outer empire.
敌人接近了
在帝国外面
It's the Prince of Hablok, Your Majesty...
是哈勃洛克的王子，陛下……
with his army.
和他的军队
Insects.
昆虫
That girl.
那个女孩
So she escaped the fire. How fortunate.
原来她从战斗中逃脱了，真是好运啊
Ikol, I want her alive
without so much as a scratch on her skin.
阿克罗，我要她不受伤害的活着
Shall I send out a small ambush party?
我们要派人去袭击他们么?
No.
不
We'll wait till they get a little closer.
我们等他们再靠近一点
Burkubane, the land of perpetual night.
布拉库班，黑暗之地
Falkon, proclaim my arrival...
法拉肯，宣布我们抵达……
and the defiance of Queen Gedren.
并向戈登女王开战
Sound your trumpet.
大声一点
Keep quiet...
保持安静……
at least till we find a way across.
至少等到我们找到进去的路
Princes do not sneak in
on their enemies like thieves.
王子不能在敌人面前像贼一样
You don't know
much about princes, do you?
你不知道很多关于王子的事，是么?
You wait here with the horses.
你在这儿看着马
I want to test this bridge first.
我先检查一下这座桥
Or whatever it is.
或者说是这类似桥的东西
It looks safe enough.
We'll lead the horses across.
它看起来很安全
我们牵着马过去
Now hear me, Gedren!
现在听我说，戈登!
It is I, Prince Tarn of Hablok...
这就是我，哈勃洛克的王子……
to revenge myself
on the tyrant of Burkubane.
为自己报仇
在粗暴的布拉库班身上
Be quiet, you arrogant, ungrateful pup.
小声点，你太自大了，忘恩负义的家伙
How dare you, woman?
你怎么害怕了，女人?
I'll show you how I dare.
我让你看我有多害怕
This should have been done long ago.
这是我很早之前就想做的
No. If you must hit someone, then hit me.
不，如果你一定要打人，就打我吧
You're not worth the effort, boy.
你没有这个能力，孩子
Boy?
孩子?
Yes, boy. You'll never be anything else...
是的，孩子，你将失去所有除非……
till you learn gratitude
and self-sacrifice, like Falkon.
直到你学会感激
和自我牺牲，像法拉肯那样
He's a real man.
他是真男人
She didn't mean it, my prince.
She doesn't know your fine qualities.
她不是这个意思，王子
她不知道你是上等人
Take that, ruffian.
看招，恶棍
Take that, you ruffian.
看招，你是恶棍
Practicing, Highness?
在练功，王子?
I thought princes did everything so well,
they wouldn't need to.
我想王子既然每一件事都做得这么好
应该不需要别人帮忙的
I was disarmed by those ruffians
the other day.
那天这些恶棍来时我没带武器
I noticed. So? It needn't be fatal.
我注意到了，所以?但这不是致命的
I am disarmed. Kill me. Come on.
我现在也没带武器，杀了我，来吧
Come on!
来吧!
You're meant to be
using your sword. Remember?
你应该用你的剑，记住了么?
Simple, isn't it?
很简单，是不是?
But it's not in the rule book.
但这不是书上的规则
You see, fencing and fighting
are two different things.
你看，击剑和好战是两种不同的事
You need to learn them both.
两样你都需要学
Will you teach me to fence and to fight?
你可以教我击剑和战斗?
If you please?
求你了?
Spoken like a prince.
这样说才有点像王子
You were disarmed
because you hold the hilt too tight.
你兵器脱手了
是因为你握剑柄太牢了
Grip gently. See?
轻轻的握住，看到了么?
Gently. I see. Like this?
轻轻的，我看，就像这样?
Your Highness learns fast.
殿下你学得真快
I think we'll continue
your fencing lessons another time.
我想下次我们应该继续你的击剑课程
We've an early start.
我们尽快开始
You are very beautiful.
你非常漂亮
When I am king of Hablok,
I shall have you at my court.
当我成为哈勃洛克国王时
我可以将我的宫殿给你
You will? My, the honor.
你真这样想么?我很感激你
I may even make you my queen.
我或许还可以让你成为我的皇后
But I'm still young.
但我太年轻了
We shall have to see.
我们以后再说
They will reach
the Ithian Cavern tomorrow.
他们快到了
明天应该能到Ithian洞穴
We must force them to take shelter there.
我们必须派人保护那儿
The killing machine will do the rest.
这个杀人机器也许可以帮我们完成这个任务
Yes. They'll make fine fish food.
是的，他们将成为它的美餐
But not the girl.
但不包括那个女孩
I want that beauty here with me.
See to it that she is spared.
我想这么美丽的人伴在我身边
看到她就这么死了有点舍不得
I'll do my best, my queen.
我会尽量做得最好的，女王
The machine is difficult to control.
但这个机器很难控制
One cannot guarantee
that something will not go wrong.
不能保证万一出现什么问题
If it does, you will be its next victim.
如果这样，你将会成为下一个受害者
The talisman, Ikol. We need a storm.
把神器带来，阿克罗，我们需要风暴
A little one.
小一点的
We should be out in the storm.
我们需要使风暴停止
Why? This is shelter, isn't it?
为什么?我们可以在这里躲避它，不是么?
I haven't got time to shelter.
I've four days left to find the talisman.
我没有时间去避难
我只有4天时间去找神器
Besides, something drove us in here...
而且，有人往这边来了
every bit of the way.
每一条路上
I noticed it, but I'm not complaining.
我知道这些，但我不是抱怨
Where's Tarn?
王子在哪里?
He promised not to wander.
Dry off, I'll go find him.
他说过不会走开的
你在这儿烘干衣服，我去找他
Look at this.
看看这个
It must be the biggest in the world.
这一定是世界上最大的
Could be fake.
There's a lot of bad stuff around.
可能是假的
这附近有很多脏东西
This pearl can rebuild Hablok...
这颗珍珠能用来重建哈勃洛克……
fill its treasury, buy me an army.
用它填满国库，用来建一支军队
Dig it out!
挖走它
Your Highness,
it may belong to somebody.
殿下
它可能属于某人所有
It does, and he wants it now!
是的，并且他马上要!
Yeah.
好吧
Use your dagger, fool!
用你的匕首，笨蛋!
What are you doing?
你在做什么?
Falkon, Highness, look at the water!
法拉肯，殿下，看很多水!
Come on. Put your back into it.
来吧，把你力气都用进去
It won't budge.
Maybe it wasn't meant to come out.
它不会动
或许它不想出来
The water is rising.
You must get out of here.
水在上涨
你必须离开这里
- This way! Make for the stairs!
- Come, my prince!
这边!往台阶那边去!
走，王子!
- Get out of the water!
- Yes.
离开水!
是
Climb up here, my prince.
从这儿往上爬，王子
Tarn!
王子!
I'm coming, my prince!
我来了，王子!
Let go!
我们走!
Where is she?
她哪儿去了?
I can't kill it! It's a machine!
我杀不了它，它是机器!
Sonja, we have to blind it!
桑妮亚，我们需要把它弄瞎
It's our only chance!
这是我们唯一的机会
Falkon, get out! It can't see!
法拉肯，快出去!它看不见了!
There. Keep it covered.
这里，遮盖起来
Why have you been following me?
你为什么跟着我?
To see that you reach the talisman safely.
看你安全到达神器处
Why?
为什么?
I have to be sure
that the talisman is destroyed.
我肯定那个神器是毁灭性的
Centuries ago, the high lords of Arcadia...
一个世纪前，阿卡迪亚的高贵的君主……
had entrusted the talisman
to the priestesses...
把神器交给女祭司……
because only women may touch it.
因为只有女人能碰它
But to guard it,
or to destroy it if need be...
但要保护它，或者如果需要破坏它的话……
is still the duty of the High Lord.
仍然是高贵的君主的职责
You? The High Lord?
你?高贵的君主?
I was coming to the temple
to see the talisman destroyed...
我是来神殿看神器被销毁……
when I found your sister dying...
当我看到你姐姐死亡的时候……
and learnt that the talisman
had been stolen.
并且知道神器被偷走了
So she guided me to you.
所以她指引我去找你
Why didn't you tell me who you were?
为什么你不告诉我你是谁?
You didn't seem to want a man's help.
你好像从来不要男人的帮助
But you needed it,
so that's why I followed you.
但你需要它
这就是我跟着你的原因
I had to be sure you reached the talisman.
我得确保你能安全到达神器所在地
I see.
我看
I misunderstood.
I thought you had another reason.
我误解了
我认为你有别的目的
I did.
是的
No. I'm under a vow.
不，我发过誓
No man may have me
unless he has beaten me in a fair fight.
没有人能得到我除非他能打败我
So the only man that can have you
is one who has tried to kill you.
也就是说只有设法杀了你的男人才能得到你
That's logic.
很有逻辑性
If you yield only to a conqueror,
then prepare to be conquered.
如果你只屈服于征服者
那就整备被征服
Don't be a fool. I don't want to kill you.
别这么傻，我没想过要杀你
Try it.
试过再说
Come on.
来吧
Keep it down over there.
We're trying to sleep.
到那边打去
我们正在睡觉
Are you all right?
你没事吧?
Yes, Prince. We were just practicing.
是的，王子，我们只是在练习而已
Then let me down!
放我下去
Thank you.
谢谢
Why does she fight so hard?
为什么她打得这么激烈?
She doesn't want to win.
她没想过要赢
Gedren's army.
Another kingdom enslaved.
戈登的军队
又一个王国被征服了
The talisman! We must find a way in.
那个神器!我们必须找到一条路进去
We'll have to climb.
我们攀爬进去
Three of us should go in.
我们中3个人必须去
Who'll stand guard this doorway,
the post of danger?
谁可以留下来守这道门
这个危险的工作?
- Falkon?
- Me? Here?
法拉肯?
我?这里?
I don't know what's coming out that door.
No, I am going up.
我不知道出了这道门会发生什么事
不，我能力不够
Coward!
懦夫
I'll take my chances in there.
我留下来
And I have to go in.
我继续往前
I'll stay.
我留下来吧
Take care, Your Highness.
小心点，殿下
Thank you.
谢谢
Tomorrow, I start my diet.
明天，我要开始减肥
Majesty, the talisman
is almost beyond control.
陛下，神器已经快无法控制了
We must bury it in the dark
before it is too late!
我们必须把它埋在暗处
现在做还不晚!
It'll be buried when I have no further use
for it, and that time is not yet.
它会在对我们没用之后再埋掉
那时也还不迟
But it will kill us all!
O God, Majesty, what do you want?
但它会杀了我们!
哦，天哪，陛下，你想干什么?
Our vaults are brimming with gold.
Great states live in terror of us!
我们的金库已充满黄金
就算是最强大的国家现在也害怕我们
- What more is there?
- The world, Ikol!
我们该知足了?
世界，阿克罗!
Today we took another piece
of the city of Toktyl.
今天我们只是拿下塔克特城的另一部分
But I have wider claims
and the talisman will enforce them!
但现在我又有更大的欲望，
而神器能使我的欲望实现!
Madness. There will be no world.
疯了，世界将毁灭了
There will be no world.
世界将毁灭了
We must find the talisman.
Only I can touch it, remember.
我们必须找到神器
记住，只有我能碰它
You take that way, I'll go the other way.
Falkon, you take the center.
你走那条路，我走这条路
法拉肯，你走中间那条
How's the food around here?
身边怎么这么多食物?
Who are you?
你是谁?
- Look for the talisman.
- Yeah. Right.
去找神器
好的，马上去
- Ikol, Gedren's black spider.
- You.
阿克罗，你这个戈登的爪牙
你是?
Yes. Prince Tarn of Hablok:
对，我是哈勃洛克王子
The city you blasted
with your filthy sorcery.
来自被你用肮脏的巫术破坏的那座城市
So the royal brat hasn't learnt his lesson.
看来王子你还没吸取教训
Out of my way, child.
离我远点，小毛孩
So that you can desert,
like the thief you are?
你以为你能像小偷一样逃跑吗?
With my gold?
带着我的黄金?
Hablok's gold?
哈勃洛克的黄金?
Now that was unmannerly
of Your Highness...
现在你这个粗鲁的家伙……
and rude little boys need correction...
没礼貌的小毛孩必须改过……
if they're going to grow up into...
如果他们将你培养成为……
I'm afraid Your Highness' growth
is going to be stunted permanently.
我恐怕你们的王室将就此灭亡
Now, yield, Black Spider.
现在，投降吧，爪牙
Where's Queen Gedren?
戈登女王在哪里?
She's gone. I'm so glad that you've come.
她离开了。很高兴你的到来
Please, will you protect me?
I'm so frightened.
你可以保护我么?
我很害怕
Gedren! Where are you?
戈登!你在哪里?
So the Prince of Hablok
honors us with his presence unwisely.
原来哈勃洛克的王子是这么没用的
How many are with you?
Tell me! How many are with you?
和你一起来的有几个人?
告诉我!和你一起来的有几个人?
- How many?
- Enough, Gedren!
有几个?
够了，戈登!
Get back, or Hablok will need
an heir to the throne.
退后，不然我杀了哈勃洛克王子
And your own throne, Gedren.
想办法保住你自己的王位吧，戈登
Unless the talisman goes into the dark,
your whole kingdom will...
除非神器进入黑暗之处，
否则你的整个王国将……
Prince, get Kalidor and Falkon.
王子，快到凯利多和法拉肯身边去
There's a way behind the throne.
龙椅后面有条路
The talisman, Gedren. Quickly!
交出神器，戈登，快!
You are a fool.
We could have ruled the world together.
你想得太天真了
本来我们可以一起统治世界
Now I shall rule alone,
and you will die for what you did to me.
但现在我将一个人统治了
你将因对我所做的这些而死
What I did?
我做了什么?
You slaughtered my parents like cattle.
你像杀牛一样样杀害我父母
My brother, my sister!
我的兄弟，我的姐妹!
Vermin! What were their lives
compared to this?
够了!跟我这相比那些算得了什么?
You are mad!
The talisman will destroy you.
你这个疯子!
神器会杀死你
Up here, Sonja.
上来，桑妮亚
Up here.
上来
Kalidor, Falkon, this way! Hurry!
凯利多，法拉肯，走这边!快!
Down this hallway!
沿着这走廊走!
Sonja. Over here.
桑妮亚，到这边来
Falkon, help.
法拉肯，帮忙
Prince Tarn, come back.
王子，回来
I am here, Gedren. Death to all tyrants.
我在这里，戈登。我要杀死所有暴君
Sonja, help me!
桑妮亚，快来帮我!
I'm trapped!
我被压住了!
Sonja! Behind you!
桑妮亚!小心你后面!
I can't get through.
我通不过
Falkon, pull her through. I'll hold the gate.
法拉肯，拉她过来。我来顶住门
Follow me. This is the way out.
跟我走，这是出去的路
How do you know, Highness?
你怎么知道的，殿下?
Because this is the way
I came in, you clown.
因为我从这里进来的，笨蛋
Here's the way through.
这里有路可以过去
Go. Quickly!
走，快!
The door doesn't move.
这门推不动
How does it open?
要怎么打开它?
I know. Leave it to me.
我知道，交给我好了
No! Come back, Prince!
不要!快回来，王子!
He's done it.
他成功了
We can't leave him.
Wait here, my prince. Don't go away.
我们不能抛下他
等一下，我的王子，不要离开
Save yourselves! Run for it!
你们自己救自己吧!快跑!
You, too, Falkon, you great, clumsy oaf!
你也是，法拉肯，你这个笨蛋!
Run! Run for it!
快跑!离开这里!
I'm not leaving here without you,
my prince.
除非和你一起走，不然我不会走的
我的王子
Give me your hand. Reach. I'll get you out.
把你手给我，伸过来，我拉你出来
Hablok is over there.
哈勃洛克在那边
When it's rebuilt,
you must come to visit us.
当它重建以后
你一定要来探望我们
I'm sure to need a queen someday.
我相信有一天会需要一个皇后
You'll find one.
你会找到一个的
Whoever she is, Prince, choose carefully.
不论她是谁，王子，细心挑选
I make it a rule never to take a woman
unless she can beat me in a fair fight.
我自己定了规则，终身不娶，
除非她能击败我。
That's a challenge
I might think about someday.
这个挑战将来我或许会考虑一下
What about right now?
现在怎么样?
Why not?
为什么不?
Come along, Falkon.
我们走吧，法拉肯
Come on.
来吧